<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Website</title>
  </header>
  <body>

    <section id="website">
      <title>Building the Website</title>
      <p>
        The website is produced with
	<a href="http://forrest.apache.org">Apache Forrest</a>.
	It allows you to build a reasonably good looking website without
	a whole lot of work.  There's no need to develop your own menu and
	template system.  You provide the content and it draws the interface
	around it.
      </p>
      <p>
        This site is currently built with Forrest version 0.6.  Please read
	the <a href="http://forrest.apache.org">Forrest website</a> for
	installation instructions.  After installing Forrest you need to get
	the website project.  This is available from the same
	<a href="site:git">git repository</a> that the main source code is,
	it's just a different module, <code>www</code>.  Checkout this module
	and then decide if you want to build the generated content like
	javadoc and translation information, or just the static site.  To
	build just the static site simply run <code>forrest</code> from the
	top level directory.  This should produce a copy of the website
	in the <code>build/site</code> subdirectory.
      </p>
      <p>
	To generate the complete site, a copy of the driver source is also
	required since several parts of the website are generated from the
	source code itself.  Checkout the driver source into a subdirectory
	of the www module.  From inside the top level directory of the newly
	checked out www module, run <code>./scripts/buildSite.sh</code>.  This
	will generate all of the content needed and from then on you can
	simply run <code>forrest</code> to build the static content and see
	modifications you've made.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section id="addingpages">
      <title>Adding a Page</title>
      <p>
        To add a page the easiest thing to do is copy an existing one from
	<code>src/documentation/content/xdocs</code> and ripping out its
	content.  Then you need to add the new file to the menu system
	listed in <code>site.xml</code>.  A good place to look for examples
	is <a href="http://forrest.apache.org/">Forrest's</a> own site and
	the source it comes from,
	<a href="http://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/forrest/trunk/src/documentation/content/xdocs/">their subversion repository</a>.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

