<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Mailing Lists</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section id="before">
      <title>Before Mailing Anyone</title>
      <p>
        Before posting a question or problem to the mailing list, please
	first look at the following resources:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="site:faq">FAQ</a></li>
	<li><a href="site:docs">Documentation</a></li>
	<li>
	  Mailing list
	  <a href="http://archives.postgresql.org/pgsql-jdbc">archives</a>, (Google interface to <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/pgsql.interfaces.jdbc">newer messages</a>.)
	</li>
	<li>
	  Consider upgrading your JDBC driver to the latest version.  It
	  should be backwards compatible and may have fixed your problem.
	</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="general">
      <title>General List - pgsql-jdbc@postgresql.org</title>
      <p>
        This mailing list is for all PostgreSQL Java/JDBC related discussions.
	This is the place for bug reports, feature requests, help with
	problem solving, and pretty much anything involving Java and
	PostgreSQL.  Messages from people who are not subscribed to the list
	will be held for moderator approval in an effort to cut down on spam.
	Archives and subscription information is available on the main
	<a href="http://archives.postgresql.org/pgsql-jdbc/">PostgreSQL site</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
        When asking for help or reporting a problem please try to include
	as much information as possible.  Good things to note are:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>JDBC driver build number</li>
	<li>Server version</li>
	<li>Exact error message and stacktrace</li>
	<li>What you were doing, ideally in code form</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="commits">
      <title>Commit Messages - jdbc-commits@pgfoundry.org</title>
      <p>
        This mailing list is for people interested in carefully monitoring
	the development process.  Every commit to the CVS repository sends
	out an email with the log message and links to diffs.  This list
	is not intended for people to post to (except perhaps in response
	to a specific commit) and questions will not be answered here.
	For more information on the list (subscriptions/archives) please see
	the <a href="http://lists.pgfoundry.org/mailman/listinfo/jdbc-commits">pgfoundry site</a>.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

